# **Bintang Tobing**

+6281262845980 | hello@bintangtobing.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/bintangtobing

## SUMMARY

I think my final dream is to become a musician, make music, compose song lyrics while sipping coffee in a music studio. I currently don't have any degree but my music hobby has been around since I was 7 years old. And at that time I felt less about this kind of thing. I wanted to learn something different, and then I found something interesting, which is design. Starting from learning photo manipulation, painting design in Photoshop, at that time I studied Photoshop 6.0 and had not yet touched the creative suite version of Photoshop. At that time, until I reached the age of 13, I started to feel a little bored with the design. Here I accepted my first job in a very new and challenging way. Because this is something that is completely different from what I have ever experienced, namely creating a site that contains simple information, is fairly simple but challenging because it is very new. Of course, I accepted and I tried the new thing (I mean seriously, how can I finish a project with zero knowledge?), And as a result, I was able and finished the project within 30 days. While I was deep in, front-end development, I was able to combine my creativity with code, applying responsive design principles. Difficult but very satisfying. I can shape, be shaped but I keep my creativity intact. And then, I challenge to study and deepen, back-end development, on the other hand, I also like things that have logic. I thought this was impossible for me to learn, but after trying it, learning Model View Create (MVC), learning the Create Read Update Delete (CRUD) method, trying to merge my project to make it visible on GitHub account, it's not as difficult as I thought. So far I have C ++, SQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS, VueJs, Bootstrap, Laravel, PHP, jQuery, and also git / github. I'm also studying to React, Node.Js. It's crazy, I'm still very enthusiastic about programming technology for the future, frameworks, crazy ideas, or other principles that maybe I can integrate into the coding in my head. bintangtobing.com facebook.com/bintangitobing instagram.com /bintangjtobing

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **Chief Technology Officer**

Infinity Solutions | PT Benua Solusi Teknologi

March 2019 - Present

1. Design, implement, and develop a client project that already provides an initial description, a rough system, and an initial fee to be completed immediately. 2. Ensuring all web application systems from both the client project and the internal office run smoothly without any problems. 3. Ensure and maintain all mail servers from either the VPS or the server run smoothly without any obstacles and without any viruses or intruders. 4. Handling advanced security if there are hackers or suspicions on the system or server. Innovating, designing, and realizing possible ideas to help office systems and client systems make office operational performance easier. 5. Come and provide consultation to customers if anyone asks or makes an appointment about the development of a

website or server. Our client that I handled. 1. CV Euro UPVC (euroupvc.co.id) 2. PT Sumatera Bio Energi (sumaterabioenergi.com) 3. PT Yasa Ap 4. PT ORI ginal Bird Nest (originalnest.shop) 5. PT Berlian Tangguh Sejahtera (btsa.co.id) 6. PT Panca Lestari Pestindo (pesthunter.co.id)

### Web Developer

Digital Envision Australia

December 2020 - February

2021

### **Full Stack Engineer**

PT Berlian Tangguh Sejahtera

September 2018 - May 2019

1. Ensure all hardware and software run smoothly from head office, branch offices, out of town offices. Complete the development of the ASCEND ERP application on the server that the developer continues to develop. 2. Ensuring all networks between port vendors, airlines, fleets, and between all related offices are always connected to the server. 3. Ensure a secure network at the internal office or external. Maintain, build, develop the system needed by the internal office on the official website system to date. (btsa.co.id)

#### **IT Consultant**

Metro Interior Distributors

September 2017 - August 2018

1. Oversee the management and ensure the operation of all hardware, software at the head office and branch offices. 2. Ensuring the smooth running of the automation system and server data for each office Ensure and provide unsupported networks in each branch shop. 3. Creating, developing, and maintaining a shop website from 0 to completion (interiorrumahku.id)

#### IT and Web Developer

PT BPR NBP 18

March 2017 - September 2017

1. Oversee the management and ensure the operation of all hardware, software at the head office, cash offices, and branch offices 2. Ensuring the smooth running of the automation system and server data for each office 3. Receive and follow up with users on disturbances in the system. 4. Perform routine system maintenance and inventory such as computers, CPUs, printers, and others 5. Ensure that the NBP Sys operational system runs smoothly according to the applicable system Create, manage and maintain the official website bprnbp 18, bprnbp18.co.id

#### **Financial Consultant**

PT. Victory International Futures

November 2015 - December 2016

PT. CITA KREASI LATENA

April 2015 - June 2015

## **EDUCATION**

### Sekolah Tinggi Ilmu Ekonomi STMIK MIKROSIL

2018 - 2021

Bachelor's degree , Information Technology

#### **SMK Negeri 1 Percut Sei Tuan**

2013 - 2016

Master of Computer Applications (M.C.A.), Information Technology

## **SKILLS**

Web Development

Front-end Development

Full-Stack Development

Troubleshooting

Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

Information Technology

Graphic Design

Optimization

Windows

Photoshop

Adobe Photoshop

Laravel

PHP

MySQL

Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

Vue.js

**HTML** 

Bootstrap

SQL

Adobe Lightroom

AJAX

IT Consulting

Back-End Web Development

jQuery

**CSS** 

IT Hardware Support

**Network Administration** 

Consulting

# **LANGUAGES**

English

# **LANGUAGES**

## Bahasa Indonesia

# **CONTACT DETAILS**

Phone No.:

+6281262845980 (Personal Number)

Email: hello@bintangtobing.com

Address: Medan Area, North Sumatera, Indonesia